Are ya ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
Kids: Aye, aye, Captain.
孩子们：是的，是的，队长。
I can't  hear  you.
我听不到你说话。
Kids:
Aye, aye, Captain.
孩子们：
是的，是的，船长。
♪ Ohh... ♪
♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Absorbent and
yellow and porous is he ♪
船长：♪ 吸水性强
黄色多孔就是他♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ If nautical nonsense
be somethin' you wish ♪
船长：♪ 如果是航海方面的废话
成为你所希望的那样 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
船长：♪ 然后降落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
All: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
全部： ♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ SpongeBob
SquarePants ♪
队长：♪ 海绵宝宝
方裤♪
Ahoy, Mr. Krabs.
嘿，蟹老板。
Huh?
啊？
Oh, ahoy, SpongeBob.
哦，嘿，海绵宝宝。
Ahoy, Mr. Krabs.
嘿，蟹老板。
OK, that's over with.
好了，就这样结束了。
Now why don't you go see
if first mate Squidward
现在你为什么不去看看
如果大副章鱼哥
needs any help
at the register.
需要任何帮助
在登记处。
And what are you up to
on this fine, fine Monday?
你在做什么
周一好吗？
Well, I was gonna
wait till this afternoon
嗯，我本来打算
等到今天下午
but I guess I can show you now.
但我想我现在可以告诉你了。
Show me what?
给我看看什么？
I'm introducing a new
Krusty Krab promotion.
我要介绍一个新的
蟹堡王促销。
Ah, you are?
啊，你是吗？
I sure am.
我当然是。
Who are you gonna
introduce it to?
你要是谁
介绍给?
Why, all my loyal
customers, of course.
为什么，我所有的忠诚
当然是客户。
Ha.
哈。
Anyway, we got
new beverage cups.
无论如何，我们得到了
新的饮料杯。
Wow.
哇。
There's regular, large
有正规的，大的
and the new Viking size.
和新的维京尺寸。
But Mr. Krabs, these are
all the same size cup.
但是蟹老板，这些是
所有杯子尺寸相同。
SpongeBob, this promotion
is designed to save  us  money.
海绵宝宝，这次促销
旨在为我们省钱。
And don't forget, each
participating patron
并且不要忘记，每个
参与赞助人
who purchases any drink
of our new Krusty Krab
Viking size cup
谁购买任何饮料
我们新推出的蟹堡王
维京尺寸的杯子
gets a chance to
try on this genuine
cardboard Viking helmet.
有机会
试试这个正品
纸板维京头盔。
That he found while cleaning out
his attic over the weekend.
他在打扫卫生时发现的
周末他的阁楼。
Don't you know when
you're being ignored?
你不知道什么时候
你被忽视了？
You're the only one talking.
你是唯一一个说话的人。
Mr. Krabs, it's beautiful.
蟹老板，真漂亮。
Not so fast.
没那么快。
Access to the mighty helmet
will be granted
获得强大的头盔
将被授予
to active promotion
participants only.
积极推广
仅限参与者。
And only those who
purchase Viking size.
并且只有那些
购买维京尺寸。
Mr. Krabs, what's a Viking?
蟹老板，什么是维京人？
Oh, well, um...
The Vikings lived
a long time ago.
哦，好吧，嗯...
维京人曾居住过
很久以前。
How long?
多长时间？
Uh, about 10 years.
呃，大约10年。
And?
和？
You're gonna have
to ask Squidward any
more questions you got.
你将会有
向章鱼哥询问任何
您还有更多问题。
He's the smart one.
他是最聪明的一个。
Barnacle butt.
藤壶屁股。
Hi, Squidward.
嗨，章鱼哥。
Mr. Krabs said you
were gonna teach me
all about the Vikings.
蟹老板说你
我们要教我
关于维京人的一切。
Oh, really?
哦真的吗？
Will you teach me, huh?
你会教我吗？
Sure, I'll teach you,
listen closely now.
当然可以，我来教你
现在仔细听。
...The Vikings were a race
of scholars and scientists
...维京人是一个种族
学者和科学家的
who lived before even
Mr. Krabs was born.
谁甚至以前生活过
蟹老板诞生了。
They are believed to have
discovered ketchup
他们被认为有
发现番茄酱
and enjoyed dressing up
their pets as chunks of masonry
on the weekends.
并喜欢打扮
他们的宠物就像砖石块一样
在周末。
Their favorite movies
are in black and white.
他们最喜欢的电影
是黑白的。
Look out!
当心！
And grown Vikings are known
to collect socks
众所周知，成年维京人
收集袜子
which they display and trade
他们展示和交易的
at monthly sock-trading
conventions called
在每月的袜子交易中
称为的约定
"Sock-N-Garten."
“袜子花园”。
Sock-N-Garten.
袜子花园。
Wow.
哇。
Squidward, do you think
Vikings really
章鱼哥，你觉得
维京人真的
drink their beverages
in Viking size?
喝他们的饮料
维京尺寸？
Of course they do.
当然有。
How else would Mr. Krabs
不然蟹老板怎么会呢？
come up with such
a brilliant idea?
想出这样的
一个绝妙的主意？
Do you
think that...
你呢
认为...
Can't you see
I am trying to work?
你看不到吗
我正在努力工作吗？
But...
但...
There's so much more about
Vikings that I wanna find out.
还有很多关于
我想知道维京人。
Well, then, why
don't you go ask them?
那么，为什么
你不去问问他们吗？
Thanks, Squidward,
mwah!
谢谢，章鱼哥，
哇！
"Dear Vikings.
“亲爱的维京人。
I am writing to ask you guys
我写信是想问你们
about your lives and stuff.
关于你的生活和事情。
If you would take the time
如果你愿意花时间
to answer all my neat questions
回答我所有巧妙的问题
then that would be really swell.
那么那就真的膨胀了。
Ah, Helga.
啊，赫尔加。
Tell me once again
of the time you visited
再告诉我一次
您访问的时间
those remote Himalayan
hot springs.
那些遥远的喜马拉雅山
温泉。
Uhh... A letter.
呃……一封信。
Why must you always come
in here during story time?
为什么你一定要来
讲故事的时候在这里？
But, but I...
但是，但是我...
Please, no,
you don't understand.
拜托，不，
你不明白。
I was only
trying to...
我只是
试图...
Ohh... Ah!
噢……啊！
Your majesty,
look, a letter.
陛下，
看，一封信。
How incredibly interesting.
多么有趣啊。
I must read it at once.
我必须立即阅读它。
Welcome to the Krusty Krab.
欢迎来到蟹堡王。
May I take your order?
我可以接受您的订单吗？
We're Vikings.
我们是维京人。
Our chieftain sent us here
because... We got this letter.
我们的酋长派我们来这里
因为...我们收到了这封信。
SpongeBob, there's some
Vikings here to see you.
海绵宝宝，有一些
维京人来这里见你。
What's that Squidward,
I couldn't hear you.
那个章鱼哥是什么
我听不见你说话。
I was- ohh...
我当时——哦...
Ah, are you the one
they call the SpongeBob?
啊，你是那个吗
他们叫海绵宝宝？
: I think so.
: 我想是的。
Well, we are here to teach you
all about the Vikings.
好吧，我们是来教你的
关于维京人的一切。
Huzzah!
好哇！
One of the things Vikings
like to do is redecorate.
维京人的事情之一
喜欢做的就是重新装修。
How interesting.
多么有趣啊。
And another ting
we Vikings like to do is...
还有另一个叮
我们维京人喜欢做的是...
Appropriate.
合适的。
What a fascinating culture.
多么迷人的文化啊。
And on occasion,
the Vikings...
有时，
维京人...
We've been known to liberate.
我们以解放而闻名。
What the... Hey,
you can't do that!
这是什么……嘿，
你不能那样做！
I can't believe
how much I'm learning.
我不敢相信
我学到了多少。
Squidward, I'll be
back in one hour.
章鱼哥，我会的
一小时后回来。
I'm going on me lunch break.
我要去午休了
Squidward?
章鱼哥？
Would you mind telling us
what this is all about?
你介意告诉我们吗
这是怎么回事？
Shush.
嘘。
Now that you're part of our crew
现在您已成为我们团队的一员
I guess we should
introduce ourselves.
我想我们应该
自我介绍一下。
This is Olaf.
这是奥拉夫。
And this is Olaf...
这是奥拉夫...
And this is Olaf.
这是奥拉夫。
This is... Olaf.
这是……奥拉夫。
...Olaf, Olaf, Olaf.
...奥拉夫，奥拉夫，奥拉夫。
And, um... Um?
而且，嗯……嗯？
Olaf.
奥拉夫。
So let me guess.
那么让我猜一下。
Your name must be...
你的名字一定是...
That's right, Gordon.
没错，戈登。
Nice to meet ya.
很高兴认识你。
Now before I put you two to work
现在在我让你们两个去工作之前
I wanna know what...
我想知道什么...
Wait, I still have
lots more questions about
the Vikings way of life.
等等，我还有
还有很多关于的问题
维京人的生活方式。
Like what?
比如什么？
Well, like...
嗯，就像...
What do the Vikings
like to do for fun?
维京人做什么
喜欢做什么好玩的？
Hmm... Fun.
嗯...有趣。
Hm, um, um,
um, uh-well...
嗯嗯嗯
嗯，呃，好吧……
What about
the shield toss?
怎么样
盾牌投掷？
Oh, yeah, yeah-yeah.
哦，是啊，是啊，是啊。
Hm, anything else?
嗯，还有什么吗？
Um...
嗯...
Ooh, what about
flaming  shield toss?
哦，那又怎么样
火焰盾投掷？
Oh, yeah-yeah-yeah.
哦，是啊是啊。
Anything else?
还要别的吗？
All: Ehh...
全体：呃……
: Ahh...
: 啊...
I, I, I can't really
think of anything.
我我我真的不能
想什么。
Me neither.
我也不。
Oh, yah.
哦，是的。
What is it, Olaf?
这是什么，奥拉夫？
We like to sing songs.
我们喜欢唱歌。
Ohh...
哦...
Vikings: No, we don't.
维京人：不，我们不。
Wait, no!
等等，不！
OK, I admit it was a lousy idea.
好吧，我承认这是一个糟糕的主意。
I promise it won't happen again.
我保证这种事不会再发生了。
Ah!
啊!
You got that right.
你说得对。
: Dah-hoo-dee-hoo.
: 哒哒哒哒。
Any other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
I'll let you know
if I think of anything.
我会让你知道
如果我想到什么。
So tell me, what is it that
you two know how to do?
那么告诉我，那是什么
你们两个知道怎么办吗？
Well, Mr. Krabs
tells me I'm pretty good
with a spatula.
好吧，蟹老板
告诉我我很好
用抹刀。
Ha.
哈。
You're our ship's
new head chef.
你是我们的船
新任主厨。
And what can you do?
你能做什么？
Well, if you must know
好吧，如果你一定要知道的话
I'm a widely renowned
clarinet virtuoso...
我是一个广为人知的
单簧管演奏家...
state-recognized
interior design consultant.
国家认可的
室内设计顾问。
Licensed and board certified
antique macrame connoisseur.
获得许可并获得董事会认证
古董花边鉴赏家。
Born and raised collector
and sculptor of driftwood
天生的收藏家
和浮木雕塑家
and able to recognize
over 1300 brand names
并且能够认出
超过1300个品牌
of single-person pedal-operated
vehicles at a single glance.
单人踏板操作
车辆一目了然。
Plus, I make
a killer souffle.
另外，我做
杀手蛋奶酥。
Impressive.
感人的。
You'll be the ship's
bathroom attendant.
你将成为这艘船的
浴室服务员。
A promotion-
congratulations, Squidward.
促销活动——
恭喜你，章鱼哥。
Hold it right
there, whiskers.
保持正确
那里，胡须。
Let's not forget
you're the one
我们不要忘记
你就是那个
who dragged me onto
this crate in the first place.
谁把我拖上了
首先是这个箱子。
Now you ask me to pour
my heart out, and this is
the respect I get?
现在你要我倒
我心碎了，这就是
我得到的尊重？
Well, you got another
thing coming, honey.
好吧，你还有另一个
事情即将发生，亲爱的。
I want off this
boat pronto.
我想摆脱这个
船很快。
On second thought,
bathroom attendants
make decent tips.
再一想，
浴室服务员
做出体面的提示。
Well, look on
the bright side, Squidward.
嗯，看一下
光明的一面，章鱼哥。
No more living
next door to SpongeBob.
不再生活
海绵宝宝的隔壁。
Let her rip, Jack-o.
让她撕裂吧，杰克。
SpongeBob: Wait!
海绵宝宝：等等！
You can't do that.
你不能那样做。
You mean to question
the will of the tribe?
你的意思是质疑
部落的意志？
If it means saving
my best friend... Then, yes.
如果这意味着节省
我最好的朋友...那么，是的。
Then... Pick up the weapon
然后……拿起武器
and fight with me a duel in
accordance with the prophecy.
和我决斗
依照预言。
All:  : Duel, duel...
全部：：决斗，决斗……
Duel, duel...
决斗，决斗……
Go on,
pick it up.
继续，
捡起来。
But...
但...
Go on, weakling.
继续吧，弱者。
Owned  .
拥有。
But, but I...
但是，但是我...
We're being attacked
by a giant monster.
我们正在受到攻击
由一个巨大的怪物。
This is the end...
这就是结局...
The end of the Vikings.
维京人的终结。
Oh, Valhalla,
why have you forsaken us?
哦，瓦尔哈拉，
你为什么抛弃我们？
Guys, you just ran
into a piece of ice.
伙计们，你们刚刚跑了
变成一块冰。
No one's forsaken you.
没有人抛弃你。
There's a breach
in the hull over there.
有一个突破口
在那边的船体里。
You just gotta
patch it up.
你只需要
修补它。
Quick, everybody
take one of these.
大家快点
采取其中之一。
What's that for?
那是干什么用的？
It's a security blanket.
这是一条安全毯。
How ya gonna patch up
a leak with that?
你要怎样修补
泄漏了？
We're not...
我们不是...
But it makes us
feel so much better.
但它让我们
感觉好多了。
Hey, you forgot
your blanket.
嘿，你忘了
你的毯子。
What the barnacles
is going on down there?
什么是藤壶
下面有什么事吗？
Dah!
呸！
It's all yours.
都是你的了。
Thanks.
谢谢。
There.
那里。
Look up there,
what's he doing?
抬头看那儿，
他在做什么？
Here goes nothing.
这里什么也没有发生。
Now that's what I Call
现在这就是我所说的
a Viking size adventure.
维京规模的冒险。
You'll never escape
this time, Man Ray.
你永远无法逃脱
这次是曼·雷。
Our molecular bubble
我们的分子气泡
is impenetrable.
是坚不可摧的。
That's exactly
what I was hoping for.
正是如此
我所希望的。
Uh-oh.
呃哦。
Stop!
停止！
Thanks for making this easy.
感谢您让这一切变得简单。
Till next time...
直到下次...
Announcer: You just enjoyed
another exciting episode
播音员：你刚刚享受了
另一个激动人心的情节
of "Mermaid Man
and Barnacle Boy"
《人鱼男》
和藤壶男孩”
brought to you
by the new "Mermaid Man
and Barnacle Boy" book.
带给你
由新的“美人鱼男人
和藤壶男孩》一书。
for the first time
首次
we learn of these legendary
super heroes' origins
我们了解到这些传奇人物
超级英雄的起源
and their rise to stardom.
以及他们的明星之路。
Tomorrow, Mermaid Man
and Barnacle Boy
明天，人鱼男
和藤壶男孩
will appear in the flesh
signing their new book.
将会以肉身的形式出现
签署他们的新书。
Don't delay.
不要拖延。
Arrive early to make sure
you get your copy signed.
提早到达以确保
您将获得您的副本签名。
Doors open at 8:00 A.M.
上午 8:00 开门
Oh, boy!
哦，孩子！
We're gonna get our books
and then we're gonna
我们要去拿我们的书
然后我们要
meet Mermaid Man
and Barnacle Boy.
遇见人鱼男
和藤壶男孩。
Then we're gonna
shake their hands
然后我们要
握手
and then they're
gonna sign our books!
然后他们是
会在我们的书上签名！
There's only
one problem!
只有
有一个问题！
I can't.
我不能。
What do you mean?
你是什​​么意思？
I'll be in boating school
at 8:00 A.M. tomorrow.
我会在划船学校
上午 8:00明天。
Ohh... Well, can't
you just skip a day?
哦……呃，不能
你只是跳过一天吗？
Just- just call in sick.
就——就请病假吧。
Always works for Squidward.
总是为章鱼哥工作。
And tarnish my reputation for
never missing one day of school?
并玷污我的声誉
从来没有缺课过一天吗？
I couldn't.
我不能。
Besides that would be lying,
and lying is wrong.
除此之外就是说谎，
说谎是错误的。
OK, hmm...
好吧，嗯……
Oh, oh-oh, I know.
哦，哦，哦，我知道。
Um, what are those things
you use when, um...
嗯，那些东西是什么
你用什么时候，嗯...
After you eat,
and you need to take a...
吃完饭后，
你需要采取...
Oh, take a,
take a bathroom break.
哦，拿一个，
上个厕所休息一下。
That's the one.
就是这个。
What if you take
a bathroom break tomorrow?
如果你采取怎么办
明天上厕所吗？
Sneak out of the window,
get your book signed
and sneak back into class?
偷偷溜出窗外，
让你的书签名
然后偷偷溜回课堂？
It wouldn't take long at all.
根本不需要很长时间。
But what if I don't
need to use bathroom?
但如果我不这样做怎么办
需要使用浴室吗？
Duh, there's always a catch.
呃，总有一个陷阱。
Need brain fuel.
需要大脑燃料。
Oh, SpongeBob, how am
I gonna feed my brain
哦，海绵宝宝，我怎么样
我要喂饱我的大脑
when all you have is your
fancy bubbly water?
当你拥有的只是你的
喜欢气泡水吗？
Well, it'll have to do.
好吧，它必须做。
Patrick, is this really
necessary?
帕特里克，这真的是吗？
有必要吗？
...Sary?
Yes, it is.
...萨里？
是的。
Patrick?
帕特里克？
You feeling all right?
你感觉还好吗？
Uh-huh.
嗯嗯。
Why?
为什么？
Nothing, nothing.
没什么，没什么。
That's it!
就是这样！
What  ?
什么  ？
I won't go to
the bathroom till tomorrow.
我不会去
上厕所直到明天。
Then when I have to go
然后当我必须走的时候
I'll really have to  go.
我真的得走了。
Can anyone tell me what the hand
signal is for a left turn?
谁能告诉我手是什么
信号灯是左转吗？
Ohh...
哦...
Something the matter, SpongeBob?
有什么事吗，海绵宝宝？
Yes... A little, ooh, ooh.
是的……有一点，哦哦。
I gotta... gotta go to the...
我得...得去...
I'd say so- here.
我会这么说——在这里。
SpongeBob: The bathroom key.
海绵宝宝：浴室钥匙。
And make sure you return
this bathroom key to  my  desk
并确保您返回
这间浴室是我办公桌的钥匙
or you're in
big trouble, mister.
或者你在
大麻烦了，先生。
Thank you, Mrs. Puff.
谢谢你，普芙女士。
And hurry back,
no dilly-dallying.
又赶紧回来，
没有磨磨蹭蹭。
Thanks, will do.
谢谢，会做的。
There you are,
young man.
你在那里，
年轻人。
Oh, boy.
哦，男孩。
Signed by Mermaid Man
and Barnacle Boy.
美人鱼人签名
和藤壶男孩。
Now I shall be the envy of
the super hero fan club, ohh...
现在我将成为众人羡慕的对象
超级英雄粉丝俱乐部，哦...
Next.
下一个。
Boy, I sure do
like signing books.
男孩，我当然愿意
就像签名书一样。
What's this
for again?
这是什么
又来了？
SpongeBob: Hi, Mermaid Man
and Barnacle Boy.
海绵宝宝：嗨，美人鱼男
和藤壶男孩。
Will you sign
our books?
你会签名吗
我们的书？
Of course.
当然。
There you go.
就这样吧。
Thank you!
谢谢你！
Mm, anytime, boys.
嗯，任何时候，孩子们。
And remember,
stay on the path
of "e-vill".
请记住，
留在路上
“电子村”。
It's stay  away
from the path of e-vill.
是远离
从e-vill的路径。
Oh.
哦。
What is "e-vill"?
什么是“电子别墅”？
Oh, for the love of...
哦，为了爱...
OK, that was fun.
好吧，那很有趣。
Now I should really be
getting back to class.
现在我真的应该
回到课堂。
SpongeBob, look!
海绵宝宝，看！
Let's go catch it.
我们去抓它吧。
But what about my class?
但我的班级呢？
This is a shortcut.
这是一条捷径。
Oh, man, wait up.
哦，伙计，等一下。
You don't even have a net.
你连网都没有。
Patrick...
帕特里克...
...wow.
...哇。
Neptune's scepter,
I don't believe this.
海王星的权杖，
我不相信这个。
Patrick:
Pretty cool, huh?
帕特里克：
很酷吧？
How'd you do that?
你是怎么做到的？
I didn't, they did.
我没有，他们做到了。
They're friendly.
他们很友好。
Wow!
哇！
Oh, boy, you weren't
kidding  .
哦，孩子，你不是
开玩笑。
You're free to go guys.
你们可以自由走了。
Ice cream!
冰淇淋！
Oh, come on, I don't
have time for this.
哦，来吧，我不
有时间做这个。
Yeah, four scoops.
是的，四勺。
Patrick, have you
forgotten, I gotta go.
帕特里克，有你吗
忘记了，我得走了。
Oh, don't be such
a sour puss.
哦，别这样
一个酸猫。
Here, I'll buy
you a cone.
在这里，我买
你是一个圆锥体。
Congratulations.
恭喜。
You're my 100th customer.
你是我的第 100 位顾客。
From now on you
can come back
从现在开始你
可以回来
and have all
the free ice cream
you want.
并拥有所有
免费冰淇淋
你想要的。
: Bah...
: 呸...
Well, this certainly
has been a glorious day.
嗯，这当然
这是美好的一天。
But I better get
back to class.
但我最好得到
回到课堂。
:
You said it, buddy.
：
你说过了，伙计。
Sandy: Where do you
think you're going,
SquarePants?
桑迪：你在哪里
认为你要去，
方裤？
You just got here.
你刚到这里。
I'm sorry, Sandy, but I just
gotta get back to class.
对不起，桑迪，但我只是
得回去上课了。
Sure you can't stay for just
a short spell, SpongeBob?
当然你不能只是停留
海绵宝宝，短暂的咒语？
I mean, it's such
a nice day, and everyone's
having a good time.
我的意思是，是这样的
美好的一天，大家
玩得很开心。
All: Hi, SpongeBob.
全体：嗨，海绵宝宝。
No, I gave Mrs. Puff my word,
and I shall not betray her.
不，我向普芙夫人保证，
我不会背叛她。
Not even for a game of badminton
with me and Dale here?
甚至连一场羽毛球比赛都没有
我和戴尔在这儿吗？
OK, maybe
just one game.
好吧，也许
只是一场比赛。
I'm serving it up, SpongeBob.
我正在上菜，海绵宝宝。
Ready or not.
准备好了没。
Patrick, do you remember
帕特里克，你还记得吗
how to play
this game?
怎么玩
这个游戏？
Is this the one where
the lowest score wins?
这是哪里吗
分数最低者获胜？
Nice job, SpongeBob,
your serve.
干得好，海绵宝宝，
你的发球。
Here it comes.
它来了。
No, whoa!
不，哇！
Hey, I'm getting pretty
good at this game.
嘿嘿，我变漂亮了
擅长这个游戏。
He's about to beat
the undefeated Sandy Cheeks
他即将击败
不败的桑迪奇克斯
at her own game.
在她自己的游戏中。
:
SpongeBob, SpongeBob...
：
海绵宝宝，海绵宝宝……
SpongeBob, SpongeBob,
SpongeBob...
海绵宝宝，海绵宝宝，
海绵宝宝...
SpongeBob, SpongeBob...
海绵宝宝，海绵宝宝……
Ohh...
哦...
Whoa...
哇...
All: Yay!
全体：耶！
Well, I had better be off now.
好吧，我最好现在就走。
Crowd: No!
众人：不！
Don't go, SpongeBob.
别走，海绵宝宝。
Think about your fans.
想想你的粉丝。
Well, if it's for the fans
好吧，如果是为了粉丝的话
I guess I could play
just one game more.
我想我可以玩
只剩下一场比赛了。
Man: Not today, yellow.
男：今天不行，黄种人。
You're playing with
a convicted felon.
你正在玩
被定罪的重罪犯
And we know he's violated
his parole somehow.
我们知道他被侵犯了
他的假释不知何故。
You might as well
confess, Dale.
你也可以
承认吧，戴尔。
Dale: Hey, man,
I haven't done nothing.
戴尔：嘿，伙计，
我什么也没做。
Oh, yeah- what have
you got in there?
哦，是的-有什么
你进去了吗？
Hm, quasi-gummy
chewy candy fish.
嗯，准软糖
耐嚼的糖果鱼。
Is this how you have fun?
这就是你玩得开心的方式吗？
By eating your own kind?
吃自己的同类？
Scum like you make me sick.
像你这样的人渣让我恶心。
Cuff him.
铐住他。
it's a shame
what happened to Dale.
真遗憾
戴尔发生了什么事。
We were classmates
back in boating school.
我们曾经是同学
回到划船学校。
He was a good student
他是个好学生
until he started
cutting class.
直到他开始
缺课。
Ever since then, he's lived
从那时起，他就生活在
the lonely life of a criminal.
罪犯的孤独生活。
Eh, eh, guh, guh...
呃呃呃呃呃……
Criminal?
刑事？
I gotta get back to class.
我得回去上课了
I can't be a ditcher.
我不能当一个弃子
Bye!
再见！
Ow- almost there.
噢——快到了。
Just have to get past the...
只需要熬过这关...
"Bikini Bottom Hug Fest"?
“比基尼拥抱节”？
Aw, does someone need a hug?
哦，有人需要拥抱吗？
No, no, nah-nah-nah,
not now, please.
不，不，不，不，不，
现在不行，拜托。
Don't fight the love, kid.
别与爱抗争，孩子。
Miss, if you don't
let me go right now
小姐，如果你不
让我现在就走
I'm gonna have to turn
into a criminal.
我将不得不转身
变成一个罪犯。
Wha!
世界卫生大会！
That sounded
like a threat.
那听起来
就像威胁一样。
I am so sorry.
我很抱歉。
Whoa!
哇！
The tar pits?
焦油坑？
Oh, I'm sinking, I'm...
哦，我要沉下去了，我……
I guess this
is the end, SquarePants.
我猜这个
结束了，方裤。
But like the old saying goes:
但正如那句老话所说：
"Better to end up sinking into
a prehistoric lake Of tar
“最好最终陷入
史前焦油湖
than to turn to
a life of crime."
而不是转向
犯罪的一生。”
Good-bye, world,
good-bye, Mrs. Puff.
再见，世界，
再见，普芙夫人。
I'll always cherish
those last kind words
我会永远珍惜
最后那些善意的话
that you said to me.
你对我说的。
"Make sure you return that
bathroom key to my desk
“确保你归还了
我书桌的浴室钥匙
or you're
in big trouble mister."
或者你是
先生遇到大麻烦了。”
Oh, I never returned
Mrs. Puff's bathroom key.
哦，我再也没有回来
普夫夫人的浴室钥匙。
I can't give up now.
我现在不能放弃。
: SpongeBob,
SpongeBob, SpongeBob...
：海绵宝宝，
海绵宝宝，海绵宝宝……
I made it.
我做到了。
And a minute before
the final bell.
而一分钟前
最后的钟声。
I am home free.
我有空回家了。
Mrs. Puff, I'm really sorry.
帕芙女士，真的很抱歉。
Please forgive me.
请原谅我。
I don't know what happened.
我不知道发生了什么事。
Everything just
got away from me.
一切都只是
离开了我。
: I brought back
your bathroom key, though.
: 我带回来了
不过，你的浴室钥匙。
I haven't the foggiest idea
what you're carrying
on about, SpongeBob.
我没有最模糊的想法
你携带的东西
关于海绵宝宝。
But I don't have time for it.
但我没有时间。
I've got my own problems.
我有我自己的问题。
Johnny law finally caught up
to me for ditchin' jury duty.
约翰尼·洛终于追上了
我放弃了陪审团职责。
Let this be
a lesson to you, son.
让这成为
儿子，给你一个教训。
Never ditch.
永远不要抛弃。
OK, Mrs. Puff,
I'll never ditch again.
好的，普芙女士，
我再也不会放弃了
That's a good boy, SpongeBob.
这是一个好孩子，海绵宝宝。
Good... Again?
很好……再来一次？
What do you mean "again"?!
“又”是什么意思？！